<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://n.project-spectre.info/blog</id>
    <title>Jasen Qin Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Jasen Qin Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://n.project-spectre.info/img/Rei-Light.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solaros]]></title>
        <id>/2023/08/10/post</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/08/10/post"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writers]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="writers">Writers<a class="hash-link" href="#writers" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Jason Qin
GPT4</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="characters">Characters<a class="hash-link" href="#characters" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Science Team</strong></p><ul><li>Sophie Jackson</li><li>Orion Jackson, head scientist</li><li>Aria, head scientist</li><li>Anna,</li><li>Elias, voice of reason</li><li>Leo, supporting software developer</li></ul><p><strong>The Degenerates</strong></p><ul><li>John Drew</li><li>Khalil Drew</li></ul><p><strong>Members of Congress</strong></p><ul><li>Congressman Bill Haley, grumpy</li><li>Congresswoman Emilia Tyre, charming</li><li>Congressman Steven Sanders, bit dumb</li><li>Congresswoman John Richards, supporting</li><li>Congressman Lester Martinez, supporting</li><li>Congressman Stephan Jones, supporting</li><li>Congressman Michael Peters, supporting</li><li>Congressman Ralph Davis, supporting</li></ul><p><strong>Ashville Heights High School</strong></p><ul><li>Jessica</li><li>Sarah</li><li>Emma</li><li>Tom</li><li>Mr. Dapper</li><li>Parent 1</li><li>Parent 2</li></ul><p><strong>Other</strong></p><ul><li>Kate Nicholson, rep of "MeTube"</li><li>Jason, rep of "ChiEnergy"</li><li>Michelle, rep of "Mistagram"</li><li>George van Hoffman, rep of "ChiEnergy", initial</li><li>Dr. Raymond, head scientist and NationalScience or NatSci</li></ul><p><strong>NOTES</strong>:
It should be congressman sanders But people keep calling him congressman stevens</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="important-meeting">"Important Meeting"<a class="hash-link" href="#important-meeting" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>INT. LUXURIOUS AUDITORIUM - MORNING</p><p>A large projection screen displays an ominous looking solar flare and its projected trajectory towards Earth. Graphs and data points flash on the screen as a voiceover from Orion explains the gravity of the situation.</p><p>ORION:
"... and with our current state of preparedness, the effects could be catastrophic."</p><p>The camera pans to the audience. Scientists nod seriously, some jotting down notes, but we also see a group of well-dressed, out-of-place individuals - the lobbyists and their allies. One particularly influential lobbyist, MR. Hoffman, subtly checks his watch, uninterested.</p><p>As the audience absorbs this, there's the faint ping of a phone notification. The camera briefly cuts to Sophie, who discreetly checks her phone under the table. The screen displays a headline from a popular gossip app: "John Drew's New Tattoo - a Solar Flare? What's the Message? #TrendingNow". Sophie rolls her eyes, quickly silencing the notification.</p><p>As the presentation concludes, the lead National Scientist, DR. RAYMOND, stands up.</p><p>DR. RAYMOND:
"Thank you, Dr. Orion. We appreciate your... insights. We'll certainly review these findings."</p><p>It's evident he's giving a brush-off. Orion senses this but remains hopeful.</p><p><strong>ARIA</strong> (whispering to Orion):
"They're not taking this seriously."</p><p>As the scientists start to disperse, Dr. Raymond is quickly cornered by Mr. Hoffman.</p><p>MR. Hoffman (whispering but audible):
"Remember, Ray, this solar nonsense can't disrupt our projects."</p><p>DR. RAYMOND (nervously):
"Don't worry, everything's under control."</p><p>The camera follows Orion and his team as they exit, expressions ranging from anger to disbelief.</p><p>ORION facepalms.</p><p>SOPHIE (whispering):
"Well... uh, darn"</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-concert">"The Concert"<a class="hash-link" href="#the-concert" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The stadium is packed with pulsating lights, booming music, and throngs of people in a cacophonous mix of excitement and electronic frenzy. Large screens broadcast John Drew's face, his charismatic smile beaming at everyone.</p><p>John Drew, shouting to the crowd: "Are you all ready for the greatest concert of the year?!"</p><p>The crowd goes wild, screams echoing off the walls.</p><p>Sophie walks into the wild crowd, looking around curiously, her face a mixture of excitement and disbelief. She sees people around her, more engrossed in their phones than the live performance in front of them. A girl next to her is recording a selfie, shouting, "Live at John Drew's concert! (fire emoji)" without even watching the stage.*</p><p>The first band, "My Spack," takes the stage. Their lead singer steps up to the microphone and begins.</p><p><strong>Lead Singer</strong>: "We're here, we're there, we're everywhere, lack!"</p><p>The crowd, inexplicably, erupts in cheer, repeating the nonsensical lyrics and dancing to the odd beats.</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong> (turning to a nearby attendee): "What did he just say?"</p><p><strong>Concertgoer</strong> (without missing a beat): "It's their new hit! Everywhere, Lack! Don't you know it?!"</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong> (to herself): "This is what passes for music these days?"</p><p>As the concert progresses, each act is more surreal and superficial than the last. There's a band that just mumbles their entire performance, another that uses odd instruments like squeaky toys and frying pans.</p><p>At one point, John Drew returns to the stage for his performance.</p><p><strong>John Drew</strong>: "This one's for all of you! Uh Uh. Muh Ass gotta crrack in it, my coke aint gotta smoke itself. We all influencers in this wild world. We all champions, uh uh..."</p><p>The audience, recognizing the words, sings along loudly.</p><p>Zoom in on Sophie's confused expression, mouth open.</p><p>Enter <strong>GEMMA</strong> from the sidelines.</p><p>As Sophie tries to process the surreal nature of the concert, <strong>GEMMA</strong> dashes up to her, clad in John Drew merchandise from head to toe – a shirt with his face, glow-in-the-dark wristbands, a cap with "JD" emblazoned on it, and even shoes that light up with every step.</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>, almost out of breath: "Oh my gosh, Sophie! Did you see his new merch? It's totally fab! I mean, look at this glow band. It syncs with his songs!"</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong>, smiling politely: "Yeah, it's...unique."</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>, not noticing Sophie's lack of enthusiasm: "And did you hear his latest single? 'Bubbly Trouble'? It's like, sooo deep. I mean, the way he goes 'Bub-bub-bubbly' just resonates with my soul."</p><p>Sophie, raising an eyebrow: "Resonates with your soul?"</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>: "Yes! And you know what? I have decided. I am going to marry John Drew someday. I mean, we're soulmates. I can feel it."</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong>: "You and the other million girls here."</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>, earnestly: "No, seriously, Sophie. When he sang 'Drippy Drop' last summer, I felt like he was speaking directly to me. It's destiny."</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong>: "<strong>GEMMA</strong>, you're great, but don't you think you're getting a little carried away? I mean, there's a lot more to life than just John Drew and his... interesting music."</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>, slightly defensive: "Sophie, you just don't get it. It's like, a spiritual connection."</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>: "Uhh whatever, your loss! But hey, if I marry him, you're totally getting an invite."</p><p><strong>Sophie</strong>: "Uh huh. I'll look forward to that."</p><p>While the camera focuses on sophie. Slowly, it zooms in in a slowly into her fake smile of a face.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-raid">"The Raid"<a class="hash-link" href="#the-raid" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The setting is a grand auditorium, filled with scientists, scholars, and thinkers from around the world. Charts, diagrams, and holographic models depicting the impending solar flare are on display. Orion and <strong>ARIA</strong> are center-stage, presenting their latest research findings and potential solutions.</p><p>Orion (passionately): "This solar flare is unlike anything we've ever encountered. Our traditional measures won't suffice. We must—"</p><p>Just then, a loud commotion at the back of the room interrupts him. A throng of frenzied supporters wearing Kalil Drew merchandise, neon paints, and bizarre masks burst into the auditorium, chanting "Drew Power!" and waving signs that say "Nerds No More!"</p><p><strong>ARIA</strong> (bewildered): "What the—?"</p><p>Lead Supporter (yelling at the top of his lungs): "You think you can disrespect the Drews!!?? This is for Khalil!!"</p><p>Chaos ensues as the raiders run over the place, tipping over tables and pushing and shoving scientists and themselves. Some people trip over themselves. Papers fly, displays are overturned. The invaders begin mocking the scientists, mimicking gestures like correcting ones glasses and snapping selfies of themselves with lab coats, with Nerd emojis and uploading the pictures with the hashtag #DrewPower.</p><p>Orion (trying to keep his cool): "We're here to discuss a global crisis, people! Can you all not see the gravity of <em>this</em> situation?"</p><p><strong>ARIA</strong>: "Gravity? They probably think it's a new dance trend!"</p><p>Supporter with a Mohawk: "Hey, look at me! I'm a scientist!" He puts on a lab coat and starts doing a silly dance.</p><p>Enter sophie, on the side, joining late as she had homework to do.</p><p>Orion frustrated at the table. He notices sophie's entrance.</p><p>Orion (quietly): "You all done with your stuff at school?"</p><p>Sophie Nods.</p><p>Sophie, having overheard the commotion, steps forward.</p><p>Sophie: "Enough! Do you all even understand what's at stake? We're talking about the survival of our planet!"</p><p><strong>GEMMA</strong>, who is part of the Drew horde but recognizes her friend's voice, sheepishly: "Sophie? Is that you?"</p><p>Sophie, tears in her eyes: "Yes, <strong>GEMMA</strong>. It's me. Trying to save a world that seems hell-bent on destroying itself."</p><p>The Drew supporters are momentarily stunned by the figure shouting at them but go back to shouting and acting like fools... Eventually they scuttle out of the conference as some of them comment about "being bored". The conference is in shambles.</p><p>The scientists and a few Drew supporters help clean up, one of them showing some remorse but not apologising, some of them capitalising on the opportunity to make themselves look like they are cleaning up for "Mistagram".</p><p>Sophie and the group depart.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-hearing">"The Hearing"<a class="hash-link" href="#the-hearing" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The chamber's ambiance is of stern focus. Representatives of several big technology and energy companies shift uncomfortably in their chairs under the heavy gaze of Congress members.</p><p>Congressman Bill Haley: "It's crucial that we address the pressing concerns of tech censorship and its implications on our society."</p><p>Congresswoman Richards: "Thank you, Congressman Haley. Mrs. Nicholson, I have a very serious question regarding your platform's censorship policies."</p><p>Kate Nicholson (nervously): "Of course, Congresswoman. Go ahead."</p><p>Congresswoman Richards (with a stern tone): "Why are you censoring content related to solar flare preparedness?"</p><p>A hushed murmur spreads across the room. Kate clears her throat, preparing to address this grave issue.</p><p>Congresswoman Richards: "Because last week, my daughter was not able to upload her solar flare-themed makeup tutorial. This is a travesty! She worked very hard on that look."</p><p>There's a moment of stunned silence in the chamber before members start to nod at each other in seeming agreement as if the congresswoman made a good point.</p><p>Congressman Bill Haley (blinking): "Congresswoman Richards, with all due respect, today's hearing is meant to address serious issues of censorship that could impact the safety and well-being of our citizens."</p><p>Congresswoman Richards: "Exactly, Mr Haley. And makeup is a serious business."</p><p>The members again, turn towards each other and their respective party members and nod in seeming agreement at a good point.</p><p>Congressman Bill Haley: "...We need to get to the bottom of this. Censorship could have dire consequences for our society."</p><p><strong>Congressman Stevens</strong> (leans forward, trying to look confident): "Representative of ChiEnergy - Jason was it, with the imminent solar flare, how can you justify manipulating information and potentially putting our citizens at risk?"</p><p>The room goes silent. Jason visibly pales, eyes darting to his colleagues as they quietly whisper something to each other. Bill Haley smirks, thinking they've cornered the tech representative.</p><p>Jason (hesitantly): "I dont have the full details as of now, so uhh... can I get back to you on that?"</p><p>Congressman Stevens (nodding agreeably): "Oh, ok, sure. Whenever you have time."</p><p>The opportunity to press the tech mogul slips away. Haley is left open-mouthed, staring in disbelief at Stevens.</p><p>Congressman Bill Haley (whispering furiously to Stevens): "What are you doing? We had him!"</p><p>Congressman Stevens (shrugging): "I thought I was being polite!"</p><p>The scene comes to a close as the speaker declares the end of the hearing. People get up to leave as Bill Haley sits at his seat, stunned.</p><p><strong>"Aftermath in Haley's Office"</strong></p><p>The room is dimly lit, reflecting the heavy mood. Bookshelves line the walls, filled with various political and scientific tomes. Congressman Bill Haley sits at his desk, face buried in his hands, visibly deflated. The door creaks open, and Orion and his group slowly enter.</p><p>Orion: "That was... quite something, Congressman."</p><p>Bill Haley, looking up with tired eyes: "A circus, Orion. An absolute circus. We have the fate of the planet hanging in the balance, and they're worried about makeup tutorials and... app compatibility."</p><p>Anna: "It's maddening. We've been trying to raise awareness, but everyone's caught up in their own bubbles."</p><p>James: "The public's apathy is fueled by their distractions. We need a different approach, something that shakes them out of their complacency."</p><p>Orion: "We've got plans, Bill. Plans to use the very platforms they're obsessed with to spread our message."</p><p>Bill Haley, curious: "What do you have in mind?"</p><p>Orion: "Well, for starters, we've been working on an AR experience. Something that allows users to see the direct effects of the solar flare on their surroundings."</p><p>Anna: "We're also considering a series of viral challenges. Something engaging, fun, but with a clear message about the looming danger."</p><p>Bill Haley, smiling for the first time: "That... that might just work. If you can't beat them, join them, right?"</p><p>Orion: "Exactly. We fight fire with fire. Or in this case, flare with flare."</p><p>Bill Haley: "Let's get to work. Time's running out."</p><p>The scene fades with the group huddled around Haley's desk, pouring over plans, models, and devices.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="space">"Space"<a class="hash-link" href="#space" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Enter the science team.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkology]]></title>
        <id>/2023/08/09/post</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/08/09/post"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writers]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="writers">Writers<a class="hash-link" href="#writers" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Jason Qin
GPT4</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="characters">Characters<a class="hash-link" href="#characters" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Noah's Family</strong></p><ul><li>Noah</li><li>Jack</li><li>Ham</li><li>Rachel</li><li>Sarah</li><li>Japeth</li></ul><p><strong>Other</strong></p><ul><li>Mrs. Brown</li><li>Riley</li><li>Inventor Leonard</li><li>Businessman Blacks</li><li>Store Owner</li><li>Store Customer</li><li>Mother and Child</li><li>Schoolmates</li><li>Jessie</li><li>12 Desciples</li><li>Monk</li><li>Temple Children Choir</li><li>Jacques</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="at-home">At Home<a class="hash-link" href="#at-home" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>The scene begins with a gentle, rhythmic sound of droplets, a soft lo-fi tune playing in the background. The camera pans over a cityscape with buildings half-submerged in water. The persistent drizzle is ever-present. The clock tower in the distance reads 7:00 AM.</em></p><p><em>Cut to the inside of a cozy-looking bedroom. An alarm clock rings. A hand sluggishly reaches out to silence it. The camera shows the face of a middle-aged woman, <strong>SARAH</strong>, slowly waking up.</em></p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>, yawning: "Another rainy day..."
<em>She rises, stretching and heads to the window. Pulling aside the curtains, she's greeted by the sight of children in raincoats, boats navigating what used to be streets, and vendors selling waterproof goods.</em></p><p><strong>*SARAH</strong> begins her routine, moving to the bathroom. She tries to brush her teeth, but the sink is overflowing. Sighing, she uses a cupped hand to catch rainwater from a leak in the ceiling instead.*</p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>: "Who needs plumbing anymore?"</p><p><em>Moving to the kitchen, she attempts to make coffee, but as she's about to pour it, a sudden gust of wind blows her kitchen window open. Rainwater splashes all over her breakfast.</em></p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>: "Of course..."
<em>She salvages what she can, placing a bowl strategically under another leak to catch water for her coffee. She reads half-heartedly while wringing out her soaked newspaper.</em></p><p>NEWSPAPER: "And in today's forecast, ahh rain! Yes thats right folks, it should be raining today, with an almost 100% chance, <em>or</em> maybe 99.99%, cant be too sure these days. Residents are advised to—"</p><p><em>A deafening crash interrupts the broadcast. <strong>SARAH</strong>'s ceiling, weakened from the constant moisture, caves in. Debris, rain, and fragments of the roof pour into her living room.</em></p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>, in disbelief: "Oh, you've got to be kidding me..."
<em>Neighbors rush to help, some sympathizing but watching from afar. A kid floats by on an inflatable ring, waving cheerfully.</em></p><p><strong>Kid</strong>: "Looks like you've got an indoor pool now, Mrs. <strong>SARAH</strong>!"</p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>, trying to muster a smile: "Always looking for a home upgrade."</p><p><em>The scene ends with <strong>SARAH</strong>, surrounded by her chaotic living room, holding her coffee cup up to catch the rain directly, signaling her reluctant acceptance of the new norm.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-market">The Market<a class="hash-link" href="#the-market" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, in the marketplace, looking for building materials and wood.</p><p><strong>Child</strong>, looking at a floating toy boat: "Mama, can we sail tomorrow?"</p><p><strong>Mother</strong>, holding an umbrella over them: "Every day's a sailing day now, love."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, overhears, pretends not to notice and proceeds to go inside a hardware store called "<strong>GARY</strong>'s Hardware Store"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong> glanced at a middle aged looking guy that looks like he's in charge of the place, with "<strong>GARY</strong>" on his tag: "Hey, Im looking for some wood, nails, and uhh.."</p><p><strong>GARY</strong>, looking <strong>NOAH</strong> up and down: "Building something big, are we?"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, trying to be discreet: "Just a... project. Something to keep the family busy."</p><p><strong>GARY</strong>, chuckling: "In this weather, I imagine a lot of folks have taken up carpentry. What kind of wood you looking for?"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, scratching his head: "Sturdy. Something that'll hold up against... well, you know."</p><p><strong>GARY</strong>, nodding towards the rain outside: "Ah.. Cypress or cedar might be your best bet. They're water-resistant. As for nails, you'll want the rust-proof ones."</p><p><strong>GARY</strong> looks at <strong>NOAH</strong> in a half interested manner albeit a bit suspiciously as well, like someone had just walked in and asked for a bunch of things</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Sounds good. I'll take as much as you've got."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Just got a bit of a "shed" going along, I guess, ahah"
<strong>GARY</strong> nods.</p><p><strong>GARY</strong>: "Right. Well, best of luck with that. Let me know if you need anything for your shed."
<strong>NOAH</strong> nods and hurries along.</p><p>A customer notes <strong>NOAH</strong>'s anxious demeanor and chuckles pleasantly, "Its such a good day today, its a shame it seems you got a lot on your plate"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Uhh. Yeah. I suppose the wind ain't ripping my raincoat off. But it sure is ripping my 'shed' off"
Customer: "Ah that right…"
Customer, chuckling: "Well, with the way things have been going, maybe we all should be building our own 'sheds'."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, forcing a smile: "Maybe we should. Everyone could use a little shelter from the storm."</p><p>Customer, tapping <strong>NOAH</strong>'s shoulder playfully: "Or from life's many storms. Take care and good luck with your 'project'."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong> with a semi genuine and grateful tone: "Thanks. You too. Stay dry out there."
Customer, chuckling lightly: "Haven't been dry in years!"</p><p>As <strong>NOAH</strong> moves on, he overhears snippets of conversations from other customers discussing their own struggles with the weather and how they've been adapting, one chuckling to themselves and laughing at the other's expense as the other says that god will punish them for laughing at him</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="after-school">After School<a class="hash-link" href="#after-school" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "<strong>RILEY</strong>, you got a moment this afternoon? I kinda had something on my mind"</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>: "something going on man?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "Just… come". <strong>JACK</strong> turns his back to leave, waving a sign "2" back at <strong>RILEY</strong>
Later, at cafe 2</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "Remember when we used to complain about the heat?"</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>: "what? uhh well yea I guess"</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>: "though I got to say, its gotten quite a lot more humid"</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>: "mosquitoes bothering you too?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "yea yea, they sure do. But listen..."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "You think all of this is normal? I mean. The way everyone's acting and all. Like, I dont really know how to say it but.."</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>, sipping his drink and looking thoughtful: "You mean how everyone's just... going on with life, like it's just another rainy day?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, hesitating: "Yeah, exactly. It's been years, <strong>RILEY</strong>. I can't even remember the last time we saw the sun. And it's like nobody really cares or... or like we've all just accepted this never-ending downpour as our fate."</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>, leaning back and looking out the window: "Maybe that's just it. Maybe it's easier to accept and adapt than to hope and get disappointed. I mean, what can we really do?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, frustrated: "But that's just it! I feel like there's this... weight, y'know? Like we're all waiting for something to happen, something to change. But no one's taking any steps to actually make it happen."</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>, looking directly at <strong>JACK</strong>: "So what do you propose? Keep trying with the ark thing that keeps falling apart? Set out to find where the rain ends? Or just sit in cafes, complain and do nothing?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, looking a bit taken aback: "I don't know, man. Maybe we could... I don't know... try to understand it. Maybe there's a reason, or a solution. I just feel like there's got to be more than this."</p><p><strong>RILEY</strong>, softer now: "Maybe there is, <strong>JACK</strong>. Maybe there is. But until we figure that out, we've got our rain boots, umbrellas, and each other, right?"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, smiling weakly: "Yeah. Until the next raindrop falls."</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="noahs-ark">Noah's Ark<a class="hash-link" href="#noahs-ark" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Scene opens with a soft pitter-patter of rain hitting the roof. <strong>NOAH</strong> is hunched over a desk, papers scattered about, and a small lantern providing dim light. His shirt is clinging to his back, wet either from the rain or sweat, or maybe both.</em></p><p><strong>JACK</strong> steps into the room, having just come in from outside. He shakes off his umbrella and hangs up his raincoat, splattering water everywhere. He looks around, a hint of amusement in his eyes.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "You know, someone once told me that the rain is God's tears. Do you believe in that sort of thing?"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong> doesn't look up right away, just continues scribbling and calculating. After a beat, he lets out a dry chuckle.</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "God's tears, huh... If that's the case, I reckon even He's getting weary of crying by now."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong> smirks, taking a closer look at the formulas and sketches strewn across the table.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "What are you working on? Some kind of solution to this eternal downpour?"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: (Sighs) "Trying to. Every time I think I've got it figured out, something goes wrong. It's like solving a puzzle with constantly changing pieces."</p><p>Suddenly, a big droplet from the leaky ceiling lands right on one of the papers <strong>NOAH</strong> was working on, smearing the ink. <strong>NOAH</strong>'s face tightens in frustration.</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Darn it!" He wipes away at his sweat, but more drops continue to fall, threatening the other papers. "Still got all of these to do."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "Why don't you take a break? It's late, and you look exhausted."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: (Rubs his temples) "I wish I could, but time's running out. The city can't take much more of this."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, feeling a bit helpless, tries to offer some comfort.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "Hey, we'll figure it out. We always do. And if not today, then... maybe tomorrow or something."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: (Smiles weakly) "Thanks, <strong>JACK</strong>. I appreciate the optimism."</p><p>As <strong>JACK</strong> nods and starts to leave the room, <strong>NOAH</strong> goes back to his work, but not before taking a deep breath and looking out of the window, where the relentless rain continues its dance.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-science-fair">The Science Fair<a class="hash-link" href="#the-science-fair" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>The gym is transformed into a buzzing science fair, tables filled with various projects from students and a sizable crowd of parents, teachers, and curious onlookers. The sound of the relentless rain creates a soft white noise in the background.</em></p><p><em>At one of the tables, stands <strong>LEONARD</strong>, an overly enthusiastic inventor in his mid-40s, wearing a white lab coat several sizes too large and sporting goggles that magnify his eyes comically. His table is crammed with wires, circuits, a large spinning wheel, and an array of blinking lights. A sign reads: "<strong>LEONARD</strong>'s Electri-Generator 3000!"</em></p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: (calling out to passersby) "Step right up! Witness the future of energy! Rain? No problem! In fact, the more, the better!"</p><p>A group of students, including <strong>JACK</strong>, gathers around, intrigued.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "So, it runs on water?"</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: "Precisely! Well, sort of. It harnesses the power of rain, converting the kinetic energy of raindrops into electrical energy."</p><p>Student 2: "Seems... complicated."</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: "Ah, but that's the beauty of it! All these rains and no one's thought to harness its power. Until now!"</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong> reaches out and flicks a switch. The spinning wheel starts to turn rapidly, and lights begin to blink. The contraption hums loudly, causing some students to cover their ears.</p><p>Student 3: "It's... loud."</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: "A small price to pay for innovation, young man! Imagine powering an entire city with just raindrops."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "But, what happens when it doesn't rain?"</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: "Oh, we haven't had to worry about that for years. The forecast is always on my side!"</p><p>Suddenly, there's a loud pop, followed by a small puff of smoke. The lights go out, and the wheel stops turning. The crowd gasps.</p><p>Student 4: "Is it supposed to do that?"</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: (trying to maintain composure) "Just a minor hiccup. This is why we have... prototypes."</p><p>Teacher: (approaching the scene) "<strong>LEONARD</strong>, I think it's time for a break. Let the other kids show their projects."</p><p><strong>LEONARD</strong>: "Of course, of course. Remember folks, the future is wet, and <strong>LEONARD</strong>'s Electri-Generator 3000 is here to light the way!"</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: (whispering to his friend) "Hopefully, without any more explosions."</p><p>The group of students moves on, giggling among themselves, leaving <strong>LEONARD</strong> to tinker with his contraption, still full of hope.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-hearty-meal">A Hearty Meal<a class="hash-link" href="#a-hearty-meal" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Nighttime at "Everyone Eats". Enter <strong>NOAH</strong>'s Family beginning to sit down at a reserved table 47.</p><p>The ambiance is muted with the soft hum of rain in the background. Dripping chandeliers, and patrons subtly trying to shake off excess water from their clothing. The walls are adorned with paintings, but the colors seem dulled, almost washed out.</p><p>A snooty waiter, <strong>Jacques</strong>, approaches <strong>NOAH</strong>'s table, where he sits with his family, holding damp menus. There's a forced smile on his face.</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Ah, the 'chosen ones'. A pleasure as always."</p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>: (rolling her eyes subtly) "Always a delight, <strong>Jacques</strong>."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "So, any specials today, or is it the usual watered-down choices?"</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Oh, you know, Mr. <strong>NOAH</strong>, just the usual offerings for those who can't decide between land and sea."</p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>: "Well, then. I'll have that, please." She points to item 15, a fish dish.</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Ah, daring tonight, are we?"</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: (looking a tad confused but deciding to move on) "I'll have a pasta scallion with pesto... and a glass of orange juice."</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "A glass of orange juice? Splendid choice. We definitely aren't running out of those... definitely."</p><p><strong>SARAH</strong>: (giving him a narrow-eyed look) "How generous of you."</p><p>Japheth, <strong>NOAH</strong>'s son: "And I'll have the steak."</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Steak? In this weather? Very adventurous."</p><p>Naamah, <strong>NOAH</strong>'s wife: "Oh, come now, <strong>Jacques</strong>. Can't we just have one dinner without the theatrics?"</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Of course, Madame. It's just not as fun."</p><p>Shem, another of <strong>NOAH</strong>'s sons: "I'll have a salad. And could you make sure it's not too... wet?"</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: (feigning surprise) "Oh, I'll try my best, but no guarantees. After all, nature does love its surprises."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Just like our dear waiter."</p><p>The table chuckles, even <strong>Jacques</strong>, who nods in acknowledgment.</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong>: "Very well then. <em>Enjoy the atmosphere</em>."</p><p><strong>Jacques</strong> walks away, leaving the family in a moment of collective eye-rolling.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-prophet">The Prophet<a class="hash-link" href="#the-prophet" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>The sky is a uniform grey, the rain persistent but not torrential. Townspeople move about their day in water-resistant clothing, umbrellas bobbing up and down like a sea of moving mushrooms. Small puddles have formed, children occasionally jumping into them, giggling. There's the muted sound of rain tapping on various surfaces, the main background music to everyday life.</em></p><p><em>Amidst the chatter, a group begins to gather near a statue in the middle of the square. As more people gather, the curious onlookers form a semi-circle. In the center stands Jessie.
She's an enigmatic figure, her clothes a mix of vibrant colors which stand out starkly against the prevailing grey. With an umbrella held in one hand, she begins to speak, her voice passionate yet calm.</em></p><p><strong>Jessie</strong>: "People of this town! Do you not feel the weight of the heavens above? The tears that flow endlessly?"</p><p>A curious murmur goes through the crowd. A few nod, some exchange glances, others appear skeptical.</p><p><strong>Young boy</strong>, looking up at his mother: "Mama, why does she talk about the rain like it's something new?"</p><p><strong>Mother, whispering</strong>: "Shh, just listen."</p><p><strong>Jessie</strong>, continuing: "It's not just the sky that weeps. Our very souls are drenched, seeking shelter, seeking answers. I come from Nazareth, a place many of you might not have heard of. But I bring a message of faith."</p><p><strong>Skeptical man</strong>, nudging his friend: "Nazareth? Sounds fancier than this place."</p><p><strong>Jessie</strong>, ignoring the comment, passionately: "All we need is to have faith! Faith will be our refuge from this endless storm. Believe, and you will find solace."</p><p>As she speaks, a few in the crowd appear visibly moved, others intrigued, and some maintain their skepticism. A hushed conversation begins amongst the townspeople.</p><p><strong>Jessie</strong>, pointing to the sky: "Look above, and see not just rain, but a sign! A sign that asks us to reflect, to change, to believe!"</p><p>As her speech draws to a close, a group of people move closer, eager to know more about this faith Jessie speaks of. Others drift away, pondering her words, while a few shake their heads dismissively.</p><p><strong>Young girl</strong>, looking up at her father: "Daddy, should we believe her?"</p><p><strong>Father</strong>, thoughtfully: "Well, pumpkin, everyone has to find their own umbrella in this rain."</p><p>The scene ends with Jessie talking to a small group, her message spreading, and the town abuzz with conversations about the mysterious woman from Nazareth.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-sky">The Sky<a class="hash-link" href="#the-sky" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Open with a long shot of Jessie standing in the midst of an eager crowd, her voice rising above the din. Her charisma and passion draw more and more people in, as they hang onto every word she speaks.</em>
<em>Around her, a community is forming. Makeshift tents, crafted from anything waterproof, are erected. Some have patterns resembling temples, while others look more like haphazard shelters.</em></p><p><em>In one corner, a group sits in a circle, playing instruments. The rhythmic beats of their drums, combined with the rain's cadence, creates a haunting melody. People join in, dancing and swaying to the music. The atmosphere is both solemn and celebratory.</em>
<em>The smell of food wafts through the air. Vendors sell hot soups and bread, trying to make the best out of the situation. There's laughter, singing, and a palpable sense of unity.</em></p><p><em>Camera cuts to a child, playing by the side. She's maneuvering a small wooden boat through a puddle, engrossed in her own world. She looks up, distracted by the singing, and turns to her mother.</em></p><p><strong>Child:</strong> "Mama, why are they singing?"</p><p><em>The mother, her face etched with lines of worry, crouches down to her child's level. She gently wipes rain and stray hair from her daughter's face. Looking up at the gray sky, then back at her daughter, she smiles softly.</em></p><p><strong>Mother:</strong> "They're asking the sky to stop crying, dear."
<em>The child looks up, her innocent eyes trying to fathom the enormity of the situation. She places her toy boat on the water and watches as it floats away.</em></p><p><strong>Child:</strong> (whispering) "I wish the sky would listen."</p><p><em>The mother pulls her child close, holding her tightly, providing warmth and comfort. The camera pans upwards, capturing the vastness of the sky, the relentless rain, and the sea of people below, all united in hope and prayer.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-temple">The Temple<a class="hash-link" href="#the-temple" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Open with an aerial shot of the city, raindrops hitting the camera lens. The rhythmic sound of rain envelops everything. We get an almost melancholic view of a city drowning both literally and metaphorically.</em></p><p><em>Cut to a dimly lit temple. The glow of countless candles illuminates the faithful, their faces showing a mixture of hope, desperation, and determination. Soft chants and prayers can be heard. A close-up of an old man's face, his eyes closed and lips moving silently in prayer. Beads of sweat or perhaps rain, mixed with tears, trace lines on his wrinkled face. His hands clutch a religious relic.</em></p><p>Suddenly, a chill runs up the old man's spine. He feels something cold and wet touch his feet. He slowly opens his eyes and looks down, horrified to see water slowly creeping in, darkening the stone floor of the temple.</p><p><strong>Old Man:</strong> (Voice trembling) "The temple's flooding!"</p><p><em>A collective gasp goes through the crowd. Panic ensues. People scramble, picking up their belongings and their young ones. The water level rises steadily, soaking the hem of robes and snuffing out the candles one by one.</em></p><p><strong>Priest:</strong> (Desperately trying to maintain calm) "Keep your faith! The divine is testing our resolve! We must stand strong!"</p><p><em>A mother clutches her child, her face pale. Nearby, a young man helps an elderly woman to her feet, preparing to evacuate. The temple bell rings, its sound echoing ominously.</em></p><p><em>Cut to the outside. The streets are turning into canals. People wade through knee-deep water, holding their possessions above their heads. Vendors try to save their goods, and children splash around, trying to find moments of joy in the chaos.</em>
<em>In the distance, the silhouette of the grand tower can be seen, a beacon of hope or perhaps a symbol of humanity's hubris.</em>
<em>The camera pans up, capturing the ever-present, dark storm clouds that blanket the city, casting everything in a gloomy shade.</em>
…</p><p><em>Shots of city residents getting down to practical solutions. Children and adults alike are seen piling sandbags, creating barricades, and innovating ways to live in a city that's slowly turning into a canal town.</em></p><p><strong>Teenager</strong>, building a makeshift raft: "Enough of this praying nonsense! I'm going sailing!"</p><p><em>Inside Jessie's base – a dark, damp room. A single candle flickers, revealing coughing followers, their faith clearly shaken.</em></p><p><strong>Follower 1</strong>, voice trembling: "Jessie, how much longer?"
Jessie, attempting to be confident: "Hold on to your faith! Just a little longer."</p><p><strong>Follower 2</strong>, breaking down: "This is madness! We're drowning while waiting for a miracle."</p><p><em>The scene culminates in a powerful moment where a once-faithful member stands up, confronting Jessie.</em></p><p><strong>Follower 3</strong>, enraged: "We've been duped! This isn't faith. This is suicide!"</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-tower">The Tower<a class="hash-link" href="#the-tower" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Cut to a vast construction site buzzing with activity. Workers scurry about, while others are trying to pour what appears to be a grayish, sloppy mixture into molds.</em></p><p>Close-up of a worker's hands smoothing the "concrete." He looks hopeful.</p><p>Time-lapse over a 3 days. The concrete doesn’t set; instead, it becomes a muddy puddle. Workers’ expressions shift from hopeful to exasperated.</p><p>Boss shouts, "Why isn't this setting?!"</p><p>Worker: "Maybe the rain’s giving it too much of a drink, boss!" Others chuckle.</p><p>Boss, rubbing his temples: "Alright, what about rocks? Good ol’ fashioned rocks?"</p><p>Another worker, sarcastically: "Ah yes, the cutting-edge technology of... rocks."</p><p><em>Setting:</em> The stone tower, looming high, with banners and balloons. A big sign reads: "GRAND OPENING!"</p><p>Families, children, couples, all lining up, tickets in hand.</p><p><strong>Vendor 1</strong> hawking mini replica towers: "Get your piece of history!"</p><p>Another vendor selling “Tower Tacos”.</p><p>A grumpy-looking cashier points at a sign that reads: "Cash ONLY. No rainchecks."</p><p>People at the top of the tower, taking in the view, posing for sketches (camera alternative).</p><p><em>Setting:</em> Atop the tower. Panoramic view of the sprawling city below. It’s breathtaking, but the inundated areas speak to the impending disaster.</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, visibly moved, gazes out. The gravity of the situation weighs on him.
A deep rumble. The tower starts to shake.
Panicking visitors rush towards the exit.
<strong>NOAH</strong>, gripping the tower’s edge, looks down. We see cracks appearing.</p><p><em>Setting:</em> Ground level. Rubble everywhere. Dust clouds. People coughing and helping each other up.</p><p>A distraught woman holds up a broken replica tower: "I just bought this!"</p><p>A vendor quickly sets up a stall with "I Survived the Tower" T-shirts.</p><p>Officials confront the boss: "This was a disaster waiting to happen!"</p><p><strong>Boss</strong>, defensively: "Look, my nephew assured me he followed all the safety protocols..."
Official, incredulously: "Your nephew?!"</p><p><em>Cut to back inside the Ark. <strong>NOAH</strong> in the foreground, animals and his family behind.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, earnestly: "That tower... it was the pinnacle of our hubris..."
In the background, a stack of crates wobbles and falls, mimicking the tower's collapse, as animals scurry.
<strong>NOAH</strong>, oblivious to the chaos, continues his reflective monologue.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rule-mesopotamia">Rule, Mesopotamia!<a class="hash-link" href="#rule-mesopotamia" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Wide shot of the city. The rhythmic thudding of boots grows louder. Out of the misty curtain of rain emerges an impressive line of soldiers. They're perfectly coordinated, with their polished helmets gleaming in the rare glimpses of sunlight.</em></p><p><em>A brass band at the forefront plays a triumphant hymn reminiscent of "Rule, Mesopamia!".</em> "Hmm hmm hm-hm-hmhmhmh hmm hmm.. hm.. hmm" a citizen hummed along without caring to notice the soldiers arriving in town...
<em>The citizens look on with a mixture of awe and bemusement. Some kids giggle, pointing at the soldiers' sopping wet uniforms and how the rain is making their proud flags droop.</em></p><p><em>The army comes to a stop in front of the "Cafe 2". The hymn continues.</em></p><p><strong>Soldier 1</strong> (whispering to Soldier 2): "Finally, a break. My feet are soaked!"</p><p><strong>Soldier 2</strong>: "Tell me about it. Trench foot's a real concern. At least it's consistent everywhere, from the trenches to the towns."</p><p><strong>Soldier 3</strong>, overhearing: "Remember when the worst we complained about was the heat?"</p><p><strong>Soldier 4</strong>: "Now it's the endless downpour. Just once, I'd like to see the sun without getting wet."</p><p><em>Meanwhile, the brass band is still energetically playing the hymn, oblivious to the rest.</em></p><p><strong>Commander</strong>, looking increasingly agitated: "Alright, that's enough!"
<em>The band doesn't seem to hear him over their own music.</em></p><p><strong>Commander</strong>, louder: "I said, ENOUGH!"
<em>The band still continues. The <strong>Commander</strong>'s face turns red.</em></p><p><strong>Commander</strong>, screaming at the top of his lungs: "ARGH, STOP WITH THAT ALREADY! WE'VE HEARD THAT STUFF FOR LIKE 5 HOURS!"
<em>The hymn abruptly stops, replaced by the persistent patter of rain. The band members sheepishly put down their instruments.</em></p><p><strong>Drummer</strong>, muttering: "Thought it set a good mood..."</p><p><strong>Commander</strong>, massaging his temples: "Someone just go get me a coffee. And find me a dry pair of socks."</p><p><em>As the army scatters to find shelter and warmth in the cafe, the scene fades with a few townsfolk chuckling and imitating the marching of the bedraggled soldiers.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="noahs-plight">Noah's Plight<a class="hash-link" href="#noahs-plight" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Scene opens to <strong>NOAH</strong>, standing atop a ladder, hammer and nail in hand, attempting to fix a leak on the ark. He looks focused, the rain pouring down around him. The leak is right above a sign that reads, “Ark 2.0 – Now with Fewer Leaks!”</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, talking to himself: "Alright, just one more nail should do the trick..."</p><p><em>As he hammers the nail, another leak sprouts two feet away. He sighs deeply, looking comically exasperated.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>: "Why can't it just... hold for once?"</p><p><em>A bird flies by, perching on the edge of the ark. It chirps cheerfully, seemingly mocking <strong>NOAH</strong>.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, glaring at the bird: "You think this is funny?"</p><p><em>The bird poops, missing <strong>NOAH</strong> by an inch. He sighs again.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, muttering: "Alright, two can play at that game."</p><p><em>Noah takes out a piece of cloth, attempting to block the new leak. As he's preoccupied, a gust of wind blows away his toolbox, tools scattering everywhere.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, chasing after them: "Oh, come on!"</p><p><em>As he retrieves a wrench, he accidentally steps on a plank, creating yet another leak. Water shoots up, drenching him completely.</em></p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, shouting at the sky: "Really? Really?!"
<em>An old man from the city stops by, holding an umbrella.</em></p><p><strong>Old Man</strong>, chuckling: "You know, maybe it's a sign. Maybe you're just meant to be wet."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, with mock cheerfulness: "Thanks for the insight. Really helpful."</p><p><strong>Old Man</strong>, shrugging: "Just trying to offer some perspective. And maybe suggest a career change."</p><p><strong>NOAH</strong>, laughing despite himself: "Too late for that. I'm committed to this wet mess now."</p><p><em>Scene fades with <strong>NOAH</strong>, once again, climbing the ladder, his determination unwavering despite the continuous downpour and series of comedic misfortunes.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="jacks-turmoil">Jack's Turmoil<a class="hash-link" href="#jacks-turmoil" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><em>Scene opens cloudily with <strong>JACK</strong>, sitting alone on a partially submerged bench, rain pouring, his raincoat’s hood shadowing his eyes. The town below has water creeping up, with lanterns and floating devices shining like stars. A half-submerged school or library in the distance, its ancient and steampunk-infused architecture evident.</em></p><p><em>Beside him is a wet history book, pages soaked and some fluttering with the breeze. As <strong>JACK</strong> traces a finger on a depiction of the Ice Age, the next page shows early humans innovating – creating fire, crafting tools, and clothing themselves.</em></p><p><em>He then looks towards the water, where he notices fish swimming gracefully, their scales reflecting lantern lights, moving effortlessly with the current. In stark contrast, on the other side, farm animals are stranded, their hooves deep in mud, some being herded onto floating platforms by townspeople.</em></p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, murmuring to himself: "Change... it’s relentless, unforgiving."</p><p>He looks at the fish again.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "But it's not biased. It's not punishing us. It’s just... change."</p><p>Suddenly, there’s a splash nearby. A little girl is trying to rescue a stranded kitten from a floating crate. <strong>JACK</strong> instinctively moves to help, and together, they place the kitten safely on higher ground. Little girl, looking gratefully at <strong>JACK</strong>.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>: "It's a hard world for little things."</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, looking at the saved kitten, then back at the water: "Maybe. But every hard world has its survivors. The trick is to adapt, to learn... like our ancestors did."</p><p>The little girl nods and runs off with her kitten, leaving <strong>JACK</strong> to his contemplation.</p><p>He picks up his soaked book, and as water drips from its pages. He opens it half hazardly and examines its pages, Page 50 shows an entry on the "RECENT ICE AGE" and details the types of equipment, fur, human behaviours and fire used to combat the extreme cold.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong>, to himself: "The Ice Age huh... Did they wear fur suits too?"</p><p>The scene ends with <strong>JACK</strong> standing, looking at the Ark in the distance, then back at the town.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-flood">The Flood<a class="hash-link" href="#the-flood" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The flood slowly gets worse and worse. The cities canals are cramped with boats and makeshift rafts from people trying to escape. Some slip from their houses and drop into the water... not trying to really do anything about it and letting themselves sink.</p><p>Eventually, houses and structures are flooded to the roof. Some trees and houses crumble under the strong gale force winds. The flood eventally drowns most people as some try to grasp for air. Noah's family managed to hurridely get onto the ark while trying to bucket out the water that continues to flush in from the roof and walls, the entire ark, leaking, many family members just give up, lying on the inner decks next to animal enclosures with the smell of feces, urine and a sulfurised mixture of odours from hell.</p><p>Eventually, the storm clouds dissipate somewhat the sun slowly starts to rise and shine through some of the clouds. The camera pans out, showing the scale of the carnage. The music starts to subside and the rain starts to subside.</p><p>The ark eventually falls apart as the wood that has been eaten away by termites and animals fall to the deck. Animals are let out, going haywire and letting loose other animals. The giant whale in the pool leaps out and crashes onto the deck, destroying it and causing the ship to titanically split in two.</p><p>The ark is basically broken into pieces at this point, with some half submerged. Noah and his family among some other strangers and visitors are hanging on to the pieces of the broken ark.</p><p>Noah (with a tired and giving up look): "Oh well..."</p><p>Ham tries to half assedly try to help someone drowning up with a hand. But they are too heavy and Ham couldn't hold on anymore.</p><p><strong>Ham</strong> (accidentally letting go): "Oops.."</p><p>The man loses his grip and starts to drown. The family are kind of just bored and some are just sitting down, lying back and looking up at the sky.</p><p>Jack: "well.. I guess water <em>is</em> necessary for life".</p><p>Camera pans out, showing the scale of the flood covering the entire planet. As the camera goes up into the sky and the dark galaxy. A piano piece starts to play, reflecting a new beginning.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="notes">Notes<a class="hash-link" href="#notes" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p><strong>Penultimate Scene</strong></p><p>As <strong>JACK</strong> sits on the bench, the rain's intensity grows slightly, echoing his internal turmoil. The sound of raindrops on his raincoat, the wet pages of the book, and the distant muffled sounds of the town, combine to create a sense of solitude.</p><p><strong>Little Girl &amp; Kitten:</strong> The sound becomes more focused, the distant white noise receding, making their interaction intimate and forefront.</p><p><strong>Post Interaction:</strong> As the girl leaves, the distorted sound of rain, comes to the fore. This white noise symbolizes the whirlwind of emotions and thoughts inside <strong>JACK</strong>'s mind. It's almost deafening, representing his inner conflict and struggle for clarity.</p><p><strong>Revelation:</strong> As <strong>JACK</strong> comes to his realization, the white noise starts to fade, replaced by a gentle, inspirational score that begins to swell, capturing his acceptance and newfound determination. The rain remains but becomes softer, backgrounded, allowing <strong>JACK</strong>'s internal shift to take center stage.</p><p><strong>JACK</strong> might chuckle to himself as the scene fades out and away...</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Structures and Algorithms for Declarative Programming]]></title>
        <id>/2023/08/01/post</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/08/01/post"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Declarative programming usually involves functional or logic programming. For functional programming...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Declarative programming usually involves functional or logic programming. For functional programming...</p><p>The basics:</p><div class="language-hs codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-hs codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">data List a = Empty | Node a (List a)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain" style="display:inline-block"></span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">data BinaryTree a = Empty | Node a (Tree a) (Tree a)</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain" style="display:inline-block"></span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">type AssociationList k v = [(k, v)]</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain" style="display:inline-block"></span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">-- basically an adjacency list. Could also use a map</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">type Graph a = [(a, [a])]</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">type Graph2 a = Map a [a]</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>How does haskell implement data structures?</p><div class="language-hs codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-hs codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">-- a binary balanced tree</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">data Map k v = Bin Size k v (Map k v) (Map k v) | Tip</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>[Under Construction]</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assymetric Distribution of Life in the Universe]]></title>
        <id>/2023/07/31/post</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/07/31/post"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ive thought about the drake equation and the fermi paradox quite a bit and kinda came to a view that perhaps there really isnt a paradox or problem with why we dont see aliens. The distances between celestial objects can be very far away, from a few light years to billions.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ive thought about the drake equation and the fermi paradox quite a bit and kinda came to a view that perhaps there really isnt a paradox or problem with why we dont see aliens. The distances between celestial objects can be very far away, from a few light years to billions.</p><p>Furthermore there can also be a high level of "temporal distance" as the universe seems to be around 13.8 billion years old. Civilisations could have sprung up and gone extinct multiple times or may have even developed so much during such time that they could be comparable to gods. It only took around 10000 years for human civilisations to develop to this extent, where we have relatively useful and powerful technology. And one could wonder what we could end up with given another 10000 years, let alone a million or billion years.</p><p>If string theory were to be true or there are multiple spatial dimensions that objects could move in, perhaps civilisations are able to make use of higher dimensional space and appear almost invisible to us. Furthermore they could be dealing with immense scales of structure and development, like dyson spheres and beyond, and we're still trying to find them with much more primitive technology like radio signals and visual data, which they may have already evolved past.</p><p>Other forms of life may also exist but and may be quite prevalent though primitive. In such a case, perhaps it would be harder to detect them. It took relatively long for complex, multicellular life to develop on earth but simple, unicellular life pretty much appeared as soon as the raw materials of water and organic compounds were present in good amounts.</p><p>Perhaps life is highly assymetrical in the universe; either it is very intelligent, or is very primitive. If they are very intelligent, they could already have transcended the usual lifestyles and universal laws we deal with. If they are very primitive, they might not have as much of an impact on their planet and is harder to detect from distances away.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Culture Surrounding Early Education]]></title>
        <id>/2023/07/19/post</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/07/19/post"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think the culture that kids are brought up in does not naturally lead to enlightenment and effective growth. It is basically a everyone for themselves kind of thing where the talented kids get boosted and the attention while the others that might different skill sets are generally just placed there to conform to the standards set. It does not allow an expansion of one's creativity from young and lead to a natural curiosity and interest in subjects like mathematics, science, history, etc. Teachers are burdened with 20-30 kids each and have to stay in a room for 8 hours a day. It just seems so inefficient. Think about the times when you actually get interested in something, you might spend hours on end by yourself, researching the task, reading books, writing notes. It almost happens automatically. You dont need to be coerced at all. Yet it seems we are led to be believe the best course of action is to have an "industrial" process of "kids in, kids out", where its like a factory line from "grade 1 to 12". Where kids sit down all day, having to look forward and listen for the most part. Sure there may be some interesting dynamics, mostly dependent on the teacher themselves, like perhaps encouraging discussion, giving out creative assignments, engaging with students a bit more at an individual level. But I think as a whole, it just feels quite inefficient and places too much "structure" on kids from young without them exploring these fields in a naturally curious way themselves]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think the culture that kids are brought up in does not naturally lead to enlightenment and effective growth. It is basically a everyone for themselves kind of thing where the talented kids get boosted and the attention while the others that might different skill sets are generally just placed there to conform to the standards set. It does not allow an expansion of one's creativity from young and lead to a natural curiosity and interest in subjects like mathematics, science, history, etc. Teachers are burdened with 20-30 kids each and have to stay in a room for 8 hours a day. It just seems so inefficient. Think about the times when you actually get interested in something, you might spend hours on end by yourself, researching the task, reading books, writing notes. It almost happens automatically. You dont need to be coerced at all. Yet it seems we are led to be believe the best course of action is to have an "industrial" process of "kids in, kids out", where its like a factory line from "grade 1 to 12". Where kids sit down all day, having to look forward and listen for the most part. Sure there may be some interesting dynamics, mostly dependent on the teacher themselves, like perhaps encouraging discussion, giving out creative assignments, engaging with students a bit more at an individual level. But I think as a whole, it just feels quite inefficient and places too much "structure" on kids from young without them exploring these fields in a naturally curious way themselves</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theory of Natural Intelligence]]></title>
        <id>/2023/06/25/update</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/06/25/update"/>
        <updated>2023-06-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think I have come up with an interesting theory of intelligence. It basically divides "intelligence" into two major aspects in terms of learning, cognition]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think I have come up with an interesting theory of intelligence. It basically divides "intelligence" into two major aspects in terms of learning, cognition</p><ol><li>capacity</li><li>performance</li></ol><p>and another aspect: need.</p><p>Humans have a very high capacity for learning and can learn deep, complex rules and facts. Like, the nature of weather, what causes wind, what causes death. Animals like whales also seem quite intelligent but do not have the same level of complexity in their neocortex, i.e. they may not have as much "grey matter" in proportion to their white matter</p><p>Human intelligence is also quite performant in terms of reasoning, arithmetic, planning and creativity. You can think about many different scenarios and consider many different factors when planning. And its usually quite decent, depending your current mental state. Sometimes its faster, sometimes its slower. Perhaps due to cognitive load and anxiety, or a lack of stimulus. Humans, when given the right stimulus and foundational knowledge, are capable of many things compared to other animals.</p><p>Creativity could be an aspect of "capacity", like when you have to find a workaround to solve an issue and so you leverage your existing knowledge base to identify a different concept that could be potentially applied to the problem.</p><p>Performance also implies how fast you can learn something and how much you can leverage your existing knowledge  BASE to aid your reasoning and understanding of a subject.</p><p>But that does not necessarily mean that humans have a "need" to do something or create something. You do not always need to think about e.g. what happened at the beginning of the big bang, or whats on the other side of the moon. You dont have to reinvent the wheel either, you could use other people's knowledge and works. Nor do you have to completely understand how it works deep down, just how to interface with it. Much of human understanding seems to have derived from individuals seeking out knowledge and understanding of concepts and things we face everyday. Instead of just treating them like black boxes. For example, the human body is very complex, and for a long time, it was not known how such bodily processes worked exactly. Perhaps some general details, but things like pathogens and microorganisms were all around us yet were not discovered until somewhat recently during the scientific revolution.</p><p>Creativity could be also be an aspect of "need". In the finding a workaround example, perhaps you are pressured by e.g. your boss to finish your job by the end of today. Using traditional methods, it would take too long. So you have a strong incentive to perhaps increase the performance of your brain to think about concepts more abstractly, and potentially find another alternative. In humans, this might e.g. engage your right brain hemisphere more, which may have evolved to process abstract thought.</p><p>What this also means that while an octopus or whale could potentially have pretty high performance and capacity for complex thought, planning and learning. But they may not have the right incentives to push them to leverage their intelligence like the way humans have in terms of building civilisations.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well, Damn]]></title>
        <id>/2023/05/22/update</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2023/05/22/update"/>
        <updated>2023-05-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I cleaned up this space a bit recently. Many things have happened since then. I think I let my uninformed imagination get to me quite often and its hard to know when your just making up some random stuff in your mind or when you actually stumbled upon something significant. The CSTC circuits and gut-brain axis can make humans do some stupid things, whether that be getting too tense or anxious about some random stuff or freezing them in place, repeating such a cycle.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I cleaned up this space a bit recently. Many things have happened since then. I think I let my uninformed imagination get to me quite often and its hard to know when your just making up some random stuff in your mind or when you actually stumbled upon something significant. The CSTC circuits and gut-brain axis can make humans do some stupid things, whether that be getting too tense or anxious about some random stuff or freezing them in place, repeating such a cycle.</p><p>And AI. Well guess my predictions came to be true. GPT really is becoming the new thing everyone will not stop talking about. Whether that be scientists, the ignorant masses or scammers.</p><p>I don't really know what's going to happen anymore, I feel quite conflicted and chaotic. My mind never ceases to bring up some bizzare  thought. Its like the more I do what I do, the less I feel like I really know anything at all. Like Im trying to become so open minded, considering all the possible timelines, technologies, cases, reasons for things happening that my brains have fallen out.</p><p>Persistent data structures? Functional programming? Dataflow programming? Logic programming? Proofs? Concurrency? Metaprogramming through metaobjects? Macros? Procedural programming?</p><p>Haskell? Scala? Clojure? Racket? Idris? APL? Rust? Pharo? Prolog? Mercury? Julia? Python? Elixir? Erlang? ATS?
All such languages have their pros and cons, especially on the current hardware-software landscape. Many were developed to work with existing APIs or ways of thinking. I think research languages like haskell and coq are better in this regard, so as languages like APL and smalltalk. With regard to intergration with existing interfaces and simplicity, python takes the cake, and perhaps julia too. Many tools are built using python, like APT.</p><p>I don't know what I even want either. I feel like I get quite nervous sometimes when coding and Im unable to do something that would be usually quite straightforward, even something as simple as reading the error messages from compilation with langs like haskell. That being said having easier interfaces would probably quite beneficial. Mojo might be a decent language if it gets released... apparently its quite fast and fixes some of python's issues.</p><p>I think I want something like python and haskell with rust level static analysis and safety. The simplicity and expressiveness when coding in python feels unmatched. Perhaps its also because I feel more familiar with it, like rust. But Im also quite familiar with C, C++, and JS but I dont really feel like those are as good to write in and I make frequent mistakes in them. Having optional types might be a big factor. As well as a single interface to write collections in. Whether that be specifications like a struct or an array of values or a combination. I think idris does particularly well in that regard.</p><p>I also want to be able to match on simple maths logic like <code>x - y &gt; 0</code> on a single arm like:</p><div class="language-rust codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-rust codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">match x, y</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    case x - y &gt; 0 =&gt; ...</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain" style="display:inline-block"></span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">// in addition to</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">match x, y</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    case (1, 0) =&gt; ...</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>Scala's unapply is also quite cool, I haven't made much use of it but I feel like this way of thinking is quite ingenious (I think haskell has it too).</p><div class="language-scala codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-scala codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">AddOne:</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    x: _</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    y: _</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain" style="display:inline-block"></span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">    match: (x, y) =&gt; Self(x+1, y+1)</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg class="copyButtonIcon_y97N" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>Im not quite sure how I feel about smalltalk's metaobject and everything is an object thing. I dont see much of a reason to add methods at runtime, but checking what methods you do have could be useful. That would add to the runtime storage overhead but ehh. Apparently it could be quite useful to modify the method definition at runtime if there's a bug or something. Maybe attach a remote debugger and tell the VM to change the object's method. Kind of like self modifying code as well I guess. It could be quite useful for security and pushing new features, but I have yet to see it in practice. In theory you could push out an updated method to all running instances quite trivially, without having to recompile or restart the system. Combined with a very simple, resilient hardware system, it could be a very potent method of running programs.</p><p>Im also not quite sure about logic programming. On one hand, it seems quite powerful and concise in terms of representing classes of problems related to knowledge bases and queries. On the other hand, I dont really think its better than functional programming implementations like haskell at writing up complex logic for dealing with lists. I think an observation here is being able to easily express logic to deal with multi dimensional arrays. Python isnt too bad at it, but the syntax can be a bit confusing when people use <code>arr[1, 2]</code> or when you have many dimensions and you have to keep track of what dimension it is in. Perhaps something like <code>rust-analyser</code> could help here with its automatic annotations, which could be applied to tensor accesses statically or dynamically. Maybe something like an <code>ith</code> dimension, and the server is smart enough to detect a shortening of the dimensions for example to <code>i-1</code>.</p><p>Im not sure about proofs. It seems like you can pretty much prove everything, though the turing decidability problem is a limiting factor. So you could have something where you are able to prove 99% your functions terminate and even "statically" evaluate calls if they wont take up too much space. And decompose functions from a complex form to a simple form. Maybe through graph theory or HoTT. I heard its possible, through generating different, simpler functions and testing that against the original. Paired with randomised algorithms, the sky looks blue. Dependent types are also often talked about in proofs, and is a key component it seems, at least if you want static proofs. Theres total functional programming which actually seems quite good too, but if I will sacrifice expressiveness for it, then nevermind. It seems like the gist of most proof languages involve annotating down a function to ensure that the recursive case eventually reaches the base case through e.g. decrementing the required value at each step. There can not be any steps where you might or might not return a value, you must do so, and that value must get you strictly closer to your goal by some non-zero amount.</p><p>Verification is another thing. I haven't tried out a verification tool yet so I dont really know how to make of it. Some say its a waste of time. Some say its only good for things you want to not fail under any circumstances, like a plane's software or a hospital. I think I should look into it some more, but if your model or spec is flawed, wouldnt your software be too?</p><p>Performance. Ive looked a bunch of articles and like... damn. Performance seems very hard to get right in the current software-hardware landscape. Whether that be through compiler optimisation, syscall optimisation, algorithmic optimisation, adding more potent hardware, faster and more memory, etc. On the compiler optimisation front, you have tons of ways to make a program potentially faster, often at the cost of more memory usage (time-space tradeoff). Sometimes though it could be as simple as removing redundant instructions and memory accesses, or batching them together. Maybe prefetching too, but tbh I haven't seen it been used myself, though I think LLVM should insert them (it goes against lazy evaluation though I think). I also dont even think high performance is that much of a problem. Rather its more like consistent, good enough performance. I would much rather play a game on a consistent 30 fps than having FPS spikes and valleys from 40-80fps even though the latter has a higher average fps. I also dont pay attention to variable resolution as long as its not too big of a gap, which means the flow of content is probably much more important than its sharpness or detail.</p><p>To that end, on the consistent performance front, it might be good to start off with a lazy language and a deterministic set of hardware and low level interfaces. The scheduler could possibly use a randomised algorithm though, which can be a bit ironic but my intuition tells me it could work out quite well.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update]]></title>
        <id>/2022/11/21/update</id>
        <link href="https://n.project-spectre.info/blog/2022/11/21/update"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Archived Posts]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="archived-posts">Archived Posts<a class="hash-link" href="#archived-posts" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Any post older than this is a rough collection of my thoughts. You can just forget they even exist.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-new-page">A new page<a class="hash-link" href="#a-new-page" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>I'll try to make newer posts higher quality and actually ending somewhere. With a list of edits at the bottom.</p><p>Its also getting close to the first iteration I think. For neutron on star64.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="feeling-terrible-as-always">Feeling Terrible, as always<a class="hash-link" href="#feeling-terrible-as-always" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Uhh yea...</p><p>I take my anger out on others due to the anger taken out on me by other others. And they take it back out on me. The cycle keeps continuing.</p><p>My mental state is always fluctuating. The shame and guilt and everything keeps driving me mad.</p><p>It also keeps me going forward perhaps. Well maybe.</p><p>I think a lot of my current anxiety stems from social aspects and how I feel like I may be perceived by others. I would often instinctely act in suboptimal ways. Im embarrassed to have to think of others potentially judging me or making "extreme" facial reactions or gestures at me. I remember someone just saying "...ok?". To me it was kind of rude. Just take my word for it, Im not like you lowly idiots. I dont want to have to lie or do your little cultural bullshittery to get my way. I like science and consider myself a scientist.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>